// GENERAL HELP:										
// - This file is a 'tab delimited' text file that can be opened in Excel. Be sure to keep this tab separations formatting.										
// - Do not use tabs or double-quotes in localization as they are part of the file format.										
// - All lines starting by // are commentary and must not be translated										
// - The character | is used to split item names and descriptions (cf. 'ITEMS' part)										
// - The expressions between braces {} indicate a dynamic element and must remain at the same place. In game they will be replaced by something else : a number, colored text tag, etc. 										
// - The characters \n indicate a forced line break in the text. It must usually stay at the same place in localizations.										
// - The title 'Dig or Die' must usually not be translated, whatever the language.										
// 										
// COLUMNS:										
// - ID: identifier of the sentence. Must not be taken into account for translation (sometimes another meaning)										
// - ENGLISH: english version of the sentence. Do not modify it.										
// - TRANSLATED LANGAGE: localized version of the sentence.										
// - STATUS: 'OK' if the translation has already been done, 'x' if it has not been done (or redone because of bad quality).										
// - COMMENT: add any comment about the localization here										
//								TO-DO	x	OK
// - Formulas to determine what to do, and to count words  (not for english)								"'=IF(B25="""";"""";IF(D25=""OK"";""DONE"";IF(C25="""";""TRANSLATE"";""RE-TRANSLATE"")))"	"'=IF(D25=""x"";B25;"" "")"	"'=IF(D25=""OK"";C25;"""")"
										
// ===========================================================================================================										
// ID	-	ENGLISH	STATUS	CONTEXT	TRANSLATOR COMMENTS					
// ===========================================================================================================										
										
										
// ==================== GAME MODES ==================										
GAMEMODE_Solo		Solo	OK							
GAMEMODE_Multi		Multi	OK							
GAMEMODE_SkyWorld		Sky World	OK							
GAMEMODE_UnderTheSea		Under The Sea	OK							
GAMEMODE_Defense		Base Defense	OK							
GAMEMODEDESC_SkyWorld		: An unpredictable random world composed of a multitude of floating islands 	OK							
GAMEMODEDESC_UnderTheSea		: Start in a cavern under an ocean 300 blocks deep	OK							
GAMEMODEDESC_Defense		: 100% base building and defense without any exploration	OK							
										
// ==================== INPUTS ====================										
										
INPUT_LEFT_CLICK		Left-Click	OK							
INPUT_RIGHT_CLICK		Right-Click	OK							
INPUT_Left		Left	OK							
INPUT_Right		Right	OK							
INPUT_Up		Up / Jump	OK							
INPUT_Down		Down	OK							
INPUT_Jump		Jump	OK							
INPUT_Fire		Fire	OK							
INPUT_Use		Use	OK							
INPUT_Mode		Item mode	OK							
INPUT_Miniaturizor		Miniaturizor	OK							
INPUT_Inventory		Inventory	OK							
INPUT_Heal		Heal	OK							
INPUT_LastSelection		Previous Selection	OK							
INPUT_Item1		Item Slot 1	OK							
INPUT_Item2		Item Slot 2	OK							
INPUT_Item3		Item Slot 3	OK							
INPUT_Item4		Item Slot 4	OK							
INPUT_Item5		Item Slot 5	OK							
INPUT_Item6		Item Slot 6	OK							
INPUT_Item7		Item Slot 7	OK							
INPUT_Item8		Item Slot 8	OK							
INPUT_Item9		Item Slot 9	OK							
INPUT_Item0		Item Slot 0	OK							
INPUT_ItemsRight		Right Items Slots	OK	right as opposite of left						
INPUT_QuickSave		Quick Save	OK							
INPUT_QuickLoad		Quick Load	OK							
INPUT_Help		Help	OK							
INPUT_PlayersList		Player list	OK							
INPUT_HideUI		Toggle UI	OK							
INPUT_Shift		Shift Modifier	OK	An input that modify various things (walk slowly, etc.), usually assign on Shift key						
INPUT_Enter		Confirm	OK							
INPUT_Zoom		Zoom	OK							
INPUT_Escape		Escape	OK	Used to close the current window, quit game, etc.						
										
// ==================== UNITS ====================										
										
U_player		Player	OK							
U_defense		Defense	OK	Represents players defense structures						
										
U_hound		Hound	OK							
U_firefly		Firefly	OK							
										
U_fireflyRed		Red Firefly	OK							
U_dweller		Dweller	OK							
U_fish		Piranha	OK							
U_bat		Bat	OK							
										
U_houndBlack		Black Hound	OK							
U_fireflyBlack		Black Firefly	OK							
U_dwellerBlack		Black Dweller	OK							
U_fishBlack		Black Piranha	OK							
U_batBlack		Black Bat	OK							
U_bossMadCrab		Mad Crab	OK							
										
U_shark		Shark	OK							
U_fireflyExplosive		Explosive Firefly	OK							
U_antClose		Armored Ant	OK							
U_antDist		Acid Ant	OK							
U_bossFirefly		Firefly Queen	OK							
U_bossDweller		Dweller Lord	OK							
										
U_lavaAnt		Lava Spider	OK							
U_lavaBat		Lava Bat	OK							
U_particleGround		Particle Bug	OK							
U_particleBird		Particle Bird	OK							
U_particleBird2		Heavy Particle Bird	OK							
U_balrogMini		Hell Hound	OK							
U_bossBalrog		Demon	OK							
U_bossBalrog2		Demoness	OK							
										
										
// ==================== ITEMS ====================										
										
CITEM_MINERAL		MINERALS	OK							
I1000		Grass | Requires Light and water to grow.	OK							
I_dirt		Dirt | Most plants grow on this. Can also absorb water.	OK							
I_dirtRed		Red Dirt | The red color of this dirt comes from its high oxidation.	OK							
I_silt		Silt | Deposit of sediment found at the bottom of a body of water.	OK							
I_dirtBlack		Black Dirt | Ancient sediment deposit, very dark.	OK							
I_dirtSky		Cactus Dirt | Dirt made of decayed cactus.	OK							
I_rock		Stone | A durable ancient material.	OK							
I_iron		Iron | Most common metal ore.	OK							
I_coal		Coal | Can be used as a base ingredient for creating polymers.	OK							
I_copper		Copper | Useful for creating electric wires.	OK							
I_gold		Gold | Very rare mineral that is not only shiny but also very useful in building electronic devices.	OK							
I_aluminium		Aluminum | A light silvery-gray metal used in high-tech devices.	OK							
I_rockFlying		Lightweight Rock | A very lightweight rock.	OK							
I_rockGaz		Gas Rock | A porous rock with a high volume of gas.	OK							
I_granit		Granite Rock | A very hard rock that is tough to excavate.	OK							
I_uranium		Uranium | A rare metal that can be used as a concentrated energy source.	OK							
I_crystal		Crystals | A beautiful and shiny crystal that has a strong chemical reaction with water.	OK							
I_crystalLight		Light Crystals | A rare crystal that emits some light.	OK							
I_crystalBlack		Black Crystals | The rarest form of crystal.	OK							
I_lava		Basalt | Recently formed from cooled lava.	OK							
I_organicRock		Strange Rock | What the hell is this... rock?	OK							
I_organicRockHeart		Strange Rock Heart | That is definitely a very strange material.	OK							
I_titanium		Titanium | Very useful metal for high tech products.	OK							
I_lightonium		Lightonium | This rock emits a very powerful light... probably enough to power Solar Panels!	OK							
I_thorium		Thorium | A radioactive metal that is more energetic than Uranium.	OK							
I_sulfur		Sulfur | Basic component for some explosive reactions.	OK							
I_sapphire		Sapphire | Very rare and precious rock with special light properties.	OK							
I_lavaOld		Ancient Basalt | Very strong hard rock with a glassy volcanic appearance.	OK							
I_diamonds		Diamond | Formed at high pressure and temperature in the planet's mantle.	OK							
I_organicRockDefenseLead		- | -	OK							
I_organicRockDefense		Strange Rock Defense | This thing seems impossible to dig.	OK							
										
										
IITEM_MINERALMATERIAL		MINERALS / MATERIALS	OK							
CITEM_MATERIAL		MATERIALS	OK							
I_wood		Log | A log from an alien tree. Useful for crafting.	OK							
I_woodwater		Water Tree Log | A log from a water tree.	OK							
I_woodSky		Cactus Log | A log from a giant cactus. The needles give a painful sting.	OK							
I_woodGranit		Deep Caves Log | A log from the deep cave trees.	OK							
I_deadPlant		Dead Plant | Dead plant remains. Who forgot to water the flowers? 	OK							
I_tree		Tree Seed | Common alien tree seed.	OK							
I_treePine		Tree Pine Seed | Another boring alien tree seed.	OK							
I_treeWater		Sea Tree Seed | A tree that grows in the water.	OK							
I_treeSky		Giant Cactus Seed | These cactuses can only be found at very high altitudes.	OK							
I_treeGranit		Deep Cave Tree Seed | A tree that grow only in very deep caves.	OK							
I_bush		Bush | A strange yellow bush of alien goodness.	OK							
I_flowerBlue		Blue Flower | Common flower.	OK							
I_flowerWhite		White Flower | Contains unique enzymes. Grows only at high altitudes.	OK							
I_fernRed		Red Fern | Contains unique enzymes. Grows only on red dirt.	OK							
I_waterBush		Water Flower | Aquatic common plant.	OK							
I_waterLight		Flower of Light | Aquatic plant that glows faintly.	OK							
I_waterCoral		Coral | Colonies of living organisms that grow only under high water pressure.	OK							
I_blackGrass		Black Grass | Giant black grass that is extremely fragile. It's very unstable but it can be used to produce explosive material.	OK							
I_blackMushroom		Black Mushroom | A very dark mushroom that is extremely fragile. It requires a completely dark environment to grow.	OK							
I_skyBush		Small Cactus | Can only be found in extremely high altitudes.	OK							
I_lavaFlower		Lava Bush | This plant grows under liquid lava. I must escape from this crazy planet!	OK							
I_lavaPlant		Lava Flower | This flower seems to grow under liquid lava. I may have spent too much time alone on this planet.	OK							
I_bushGranit		Deep Caves Bush | A bush that lives in the deepest caves.	OK							
I_organicHair		Hairy Plant | Looks like some sort of giant hair.	OK							
										
I_metalScrap		Scrap Metal | A piece of metal scrap. It must have come from the ship when it crashed.	OK							
I_lightGem		Blue Energy Gem | A luminescent gem that periodically discharges small amounts of energy. It emits a soothing blue light.	OK							
I_dogHorn		Hound Horn | A pointed horn with its poison gland still intact. Potentially useful with a bit of chemistry!	OK							
I_energyGem		Red Energy Gem | A luminescent gem that emits large amounts of unstable energy. Its red glow is not very reassuring...	OK							
I_moleShell		Dweller Shell | The shell of a Dweller monster. Quite a durable material.	OK							
I_fish2Regen		Piranha Regen Organ | A unique part of the Piranha that contains its incredible bio-regeneration organ.	OK							
I_dogHorn3		Black Hound Horn | A deadlier pointed horn with a stronger poison gland for better results!	OK							
I_moleShellBlack		Black Dweller Shell | The shell of a Black Dweller monster. Very heavy and durable.	OK							
I_bossMadCrabSonar		Mad Crab Sonar | An organ that emits sound vibrations used by the Mad Crab to call for help.	OK							
I_bossMadCrabMaterial		Mad Crab Material | A biological material that can be used as a catalyst for producing highly concentrated plasma bursts.	OK							
I_bat2Sonar		Bat Sonar | Bio-Locator used by Bats to scan their nearby environment.	OK							
I_darkGem		Dark Energy Gem | A gem that strangely emits a black light. 	OK							
I_fish3Regen		Black Piranha Regen Organ | An important part of a Black Piranha that contains its incredible bio-regeneration organ.	OK							
I_antShell		Ant Shell | An incredibly strong material that comprises the exoskeleton of native giant ants.	OK							
I_bat3Sonar		Precise Bat Sonar | An advanced Bio-Locator that is very precise.	OK							
I_masterGem		Energy Master Gem | A large gem that only the gigantic leaders of the fireflies have.	OK							
I_sharkSkin		Shark Fish Skin | A very smooth but strong bio-material that is also very sticky.	OK							
										
I_unstableGemResidue		Unstable Gem Residue | Part of a very powerful but unstable gem.	OK							
I_lootDwellerLord		Dweller Lord Shell Spike | This spike emits a defensive electromagnetic field, making it extremely resistant to all energetic attacks.	OK							
I_lootParticleGround		Small Particle Emitor | These leg components are able to emit a natural basic energetic particle.	OK							
I_lootParticleBirds		Particle Emitor | These leg components are able to emit a natural energetic particle.	OK							
I_lootLargeParticleBirds		Powerful Particle Emitor | These leg components are able to emit a natural powerful energetic particle.	OK							
I_lootLavaSpider		Lava Spider's Igniter | Contains an organ that is able to generate flame using atmospheric gas.	OK							
I_lootLavaBat		Lava Bat's Igniter | Contains an organ that is able to generate fireballs using atmosphere gas.	OK							
I_lootMiniBalrog		Hell Hound's Horns | Contains a very strong chemical poison that could be used to boost metabolism.	OK							
I_lootBalrog		Demon's Skin | Demons external hide that is extremely resistant to heat.	OK							
										
										
										
I_bloodyFlesh1		Radioactive Blood | Bloody flesh containing radioactive particles that can be used to produce energy. Gathered from life forms active at night. This probably explains their aggressive behavior.	OK							
I_bloodyFlesh2		High Radioactive Blood | Bloody flesh containing more radioactive particles.	OK							
I_bloodyFlesh3		Deadly Radioactive Blood | Bloody flesh containing massive amounts of radioactive particles.	OK							
										
										
CITEM_DEVICE		DEVICES	OK							
I_miniaturizorMK1		Miniaturizor | Extracts, removes and miniaturizes objects and blocks for ease of transportation. {Input_Miniaturizor} to extract (no need to select it) and {Input_Fire} to repair (when selected).	OK							
I_miniaturizorMK2		Miniaturizor MK II | Stronger deatomizer beam. Should work on rocks.	OK							
I_miniaturizorMK3		Miniaturizor MK III | Mark III, now THAT is high-tech. Try it, you'll love it!	OK							
I_miniaturizorMK4		Miniaturizor MK IV | Feel the power in your hands.	OK							
I_miniaturizorMK5		Miniaturizor MK V | The best Miniaturizor ever invented.	OK							
I_miniaturizorUltimate		Ultimate Miniaturizor | One more cheated device!	OK	"Cheating with the meaning ""overpowered"", ""too easy to play with this item"""						
I_flashLight		Flashlight | Provides a decent amount of light around you. A must-have for spelunkers!	OK							
I_flashLightMK2		Advanced Flashlight | More light!	OK							
I_potionHp		Health Potion | A gross tasting mixture of regenerative concentrate. Heals 30% of your max HP.	OK							
I_potionHpRegen		Health Regeneration Potion | The low radioactivity mixed with a special chemical ingredient helps the tissues to regenerate. Heals 200% of your HP over 60s.	OK							
I_potionHpBig		Large Health Potion | An even worse tasting mixture. More disgusting is more efficient, they say! Heals 50% of your max HP.	OK							
I_potionCritics		Precision Potion | This mixture will help you hit your targets weakest point with more precision. Increases critical hits by +20% over 60s.	OK							
I_armorMk1		Dweller Armor | Stylish! Reduces damage by 2.	OK							
I_armorMk2		Black Dweller Armor | Now comes in classic black. Reduces damage by 4.	OK							
I_minimapper		Minimapper | Display the map of the surroundings. You must first explore the areas for them to be scanned.	OK							
I_electricWire		Electric Wire | Use it to power electric machines. Click on a cell to add it or remove it.	OK							
I_metalDetector		Rare Metals Detector | This detection device is calibrated to detect only rare metals like gold, uranium or thorium up to 100m away.	OK							
I_drone		Drone | This drone should be able to serve as a body for the AI of your ship. Comes with an integrated self-teleporting device so it can follow you everywhere you go. Sorry.	OK							
I_waterDetector		Water Detector | Display the amount of water in a block of ground.	OK							
I_effeilGlasses		Eiffel Glasses | Those Augmented-Reality glasses that display the forces applied to structures.	OK							
I_waterBreather		Rebreather | This small device can get a little oxygen from the water. Be careful, it doesn't last long.	OK							
I_jetpack		Jetpack | Portable mini-rockets attached to a pack. Very heavy when walking or swimming. Doesn't work very well near volcanic Basalt (radiations and heat causing interferences).	OK							
I_armorMk3		Ant Armor | With impressive little spikes on the shoulders. Reduces damage by 6.	OK							
I_droneCombat		Combat Drone | This laser-armed drone should be able to make your ship's AI actually useful.	OK							
I_potionSpeed		Speed Potion | Gives more speed and jump force (+50% over 60s).	OK							
I_defenseShield		Defense Shield | Creates a magnetic field around you that can absorb half of your maximum health points from projectiles. Refreshes in 2s.	OK							
I_droneWar		War Drone | Now be careful, such a drone could make the AI become a little arrogant. As if this was not already the case...	OK							
I_ultimateJetpack		Ultimate Jetpack | Integrated nuclear mini-reactor, can run continuously for 50 years in any terrain!	OK							
I_armorUltimate		Ultimate Armor | Reduce damages by 100. Now the challenge is to die.	OK							
I_ultimateBrush		Ultimate Dimensional Brush | Each hair of this brush is able to pull some matter from extra-dimensional planes and reform any mineral or background in this dimension. I know it's a bit far fetched... but do you have any better explanation? (hold {Input_Shift} for bigger brush)	OK							
I_ultimateWaterPistol		Ultimate Water Pistol | Condense water from air (hold {Input_Shift} for more water!)	OK							
I_ultimateLavaPistol		Ultimate Lava Pistol | Condense lava from... hum... sorry, I give up on those descriptions. Just enjoy! (hold {Input_Shift} for more joy!)	OK							
I_ultimateSpongePistol		Ultimate Sponge Pistol | Absorbs liquids	OK	"The tool ""removes"" the water, makes it disappear, vanish"						
I_ultimateTotoroGun		Ultimate Plant Gun | Enables anything that could grow in certain conditions (type of dirt, water, etc.) to grow instantly	OK							
I_ultimateMonstersGun		Ultimate Monster Gun | Teleport a monster of this world to right in front of you. Use at your own risk.	OK	The weapons creates/spawns a monster, make it one appear. If we click very fast, it creates a lot of monsters.						
										
										
DEVICE_ACTIVABLE_DESC		\nTo trigger this item, right-click on its icon or select it and left-click anywhere.	OK							
										
CITEM_WEAPON		WEAPONS	OK							
I_gunRifle		Plasma Rifle | Still better than a wooden sword. Medium bullet range, high accuracy but low damage.	OK							
I_gunShotgun		Plasma Shotgun | Most effective at close range. Low accuracy and bullet range.	OK							
I_gunMachineGun		Plasma Machine Gun | Low damage, but a pleasantly high rate of fire!	OK							
I_gunSnipe		Plasma Sniper Rifle | Very high damage with a Long range. A timeless classic.	OK							
I_gunLaser		Laser Gun | Craft & Co at the pinnacle of their technology! Concentrated laser beams that burn through any organic material.	OK							
I_gunRocket		Rocket Launcher | Very powerful explosive impact.	OK							
I_gunZF0		ZF-0 | With the replay button, it's even easier. One shot... and replay sends every following shot to the same location. Packaged with Armor-Piercing rounds.	OK	It's a quote from the 5th Element movie						
I_gunMegaSnipe		Overcharged Plasma Gun | This is what happens when you push plasma technology to its ultimate level. Be extremely careful with the recoil!	OK							
I_gunLaserGatling		Gatling Laser | Did you like the Laser Gun? Then you'll love this one with a much higher rate of fire!	OK							
I_gunStorm		Storm Gun | Ionize an area to create rain and lightning. It has a large area of effect.	OK							
I_gunGrenadeLaunch		Grenade Launcher | Launch grenades that explode on contact. Damages any construction and terrain. Do not think about using it inside your home!	OK	"""terrain"", are the environent building blocks"". Walls and machines are included in the ""construction"" part"						
I_gunParticlesShotgun		Particle Shotgun | Deadly at close range with a strong knockback	OK							
I_gunParticlesSniper		Particle Sniper Rifle | Very powerful at long range	OK							
I_gunFlamethrower		Flame Thrower | A classic fiery death!	OK							
I_gunLightSword		- | -	OK	(do not translate)						
I_gunUltimateParticlesGatling		Ultimate Particle Gatling | Do you even have time to see your enemy with that thing?	OK							
I_gunUltimateGrenadeLauncher		Ultimate Grenade Launcher | Master of destroyers.	OK							
I_gravgun		Gravity Gun | Now you can control gravity!	OK							
WEAPON_ADD_DESC		\n- Damage: {1}\n- Fire rate: {2}/s	OK							
WEAPON_ADD_DESC2		\n- Damage: {1} (x{2})\n- Fire rate: {3}/s	OK							
										
CITEM_DEFENSE		DEFENSES	OK							
I_turret360		Rotating Turret | Has 360° line of sight for targeting.	OK							
I_turretGatling		Gatling Turret | Static turret. Use {Input_Mode} to change the direction it is facing.	OK							
I_turretReparator		Auto-Repair Turret | Slowly repairs nearby walls, turrets and machines that have been damaged.	OK							
I_turretHeavy		Heavy Turret | Slow rate of fire, but very powerful!	OK							
I_turretMine		Lightning Mine | Releases heavy damage to all nearby enemies in the blast radius. Activated on close proximity. Single use.	OK							
I_turretSpikes		Electrified Spikes | Electrocute monsters passing just above it. Consumes 1kW.	OK							
I_turretReparatorMK2		Advanced Auto-Repair Turret | Repairs nearby damaged walls, turrets and machines. Consumes 1kW.	OK							
I_turretCeiling		Death Pulse Turret | Low energy death pulse defensive weapon. Ceiling mount only.	OK							
I_turretLaser		Laser Turret | Much more efficient than plasma technology. Burn through all organic material.	OK							
I_turretTesla		Tesla Turret | Creates a powerful lightning strike on nearby monsters, with a small area damage effect. Consumes 3kW.	OK							
I_turretFlame		Flamethrower Turret | Autonomous flame-thrower weapon to burn any incoming enemies.	OK							
I_turretParticles		Particle Turret | Long range and incredibly powerful turret.	OK							
I_explosive		Explosive | Powerful explosive that will destroy even the strongest materials. Nothing can resist it.	OK							
TURRET_ADD_DESC		\n- HP: {1}\n- Damage: {2}\n- Fire rate: {3}/s	OK							
										
CITEM_WALL		WALLS	OK							
I_platform		Wooden Platform | Can be built on background surfaces. Used to walk or place machines on while still being possible to move over.	OK							
I_platformSteel		Steel Platform | Much more modern-looking platforms than the wooden ones.	OK							
I_wallWood		Wooden Wall | A fragile building block.	OK							
I_wallConcrete		Concrete Wall | A solid and durable concrete building block.	OK							
I_wallReinforced		Reinforced Concrete Wall | A much harder and more durable concrete building block.	OK							
I_wallDoor		Armored Door | A very resistant reinforced door. Great for air locks! If attached to an electric wire, cannot be opened manually but by electric signal.	OK							
I_waterPump		Water Pump | Transfer water from one side to the other. Consumes 4kW.	OK							
I_wallComposite		Composite Wall | Fiber-reinforced composite concrete wall.	OK							
I_wallCompositeLight		Composite Light Wall | A low-density high resistant concrete wall.	OK							
I_wallIronSupport		Iron Support | A scaffolding support structure that you can move through!	OK							
I_wallCompositeSupport		Composite Metal Support | Advanced alloy girder supports.	OK							
I_backwall		Concrete Back Wall | Built on the background layer. Supports only itself. Prevent monsters to spawn.	OK	Layers are vertical planes : the foreground layer is in front of the player, the background is behind it. Here I talk about the dirt and rock in the background, the ones that the player cannot mine.						
I_wallUltimate		Ultimate Wall | This must be made of Ultimatonium, or something like that. 	OK							
WALL_ADD_DESC		\n- Resistance: {1}\n- Weight: {2}	OK							
										
CITEM_MACHINE		MACHINES	OK							
I_autoBuilderMK1		Auto-Builder | Once placed, use {Input_Use} to interact with it to craft a variety of Tier 1 items.	OK							
I_autoBuilderMK2		Auto-Builder MK II | To craft a variety of Tier 2 items.	OK							
I_autoBuilderMK3		Auto-Builder MK III | To craft a variety of Tier 3 items.	OK							
I_autoBuilderMK4		Auto-Builder MK IV | To craft a variety of Tier 4 items.	OK							
I_autoBuilderMK5		Auto-Builder MK V | To craft a variety of Tier 5 items.	OK							
I_autoBuilderUltimate		Ultimate Auto-Builder | Includes a matter generator to create atoms from scratch. No need for materials anymore!	OK							
I_light		Lamp | Shiny, waterproof lighting! Place them nearby if you are afraid of what might be hiding in the dark.	OK							
I_lightSticky		Wall Light | You can attach this lamp to any surface.	OK							
I_generatorSun		Solar Panel | Produces electricity from sun light (1kW).	OK							
I_lightSun		Sun Light | This ceiling light emits enough power to make plants able to grow where no sunlight is available. Consumes 1kW.	OK							
I_teleport		Teleporter | State of the art Craft & Co transportation technology! Consumes 3kW. Only the entrance needs to be powered. \nPress {Input_Use} to show arrows pointing to the exit teleporters (unpowered ones are displayed in dark blue), then press {Input_Use} over an arrow to teleport.	OK							
I_reactor		Thorium Reactor | Autonomous Thorium mini-reactor. Produces 5kW of energy, with at least 10 years of autonomy.	OK							
I_elecSwitch		Toggle Switch | Press the button to open or close the circuit between the two outlets on its right.	OK	outlets are the small things where you can attach electric wires						
I_elecSwitchPush		Push Switch | Press the button to close the circuit between the two outlets on its right, for a very short time.	OK							
I_elecSwitchRelay		Relay Switch | Closes the circuit between the two right outlets if the bottom-left outlet is powered.	OK	There can be 4 outlets for items, in the 4 corners of a block. Exemple of electricity: https://pbs.twimg.com/media/ChIm-ngUoAAo8Mh.jpg. The purple squares are the outlets						
I_elecCross		Wire Crossing | Enables you to cross two independent wire circuits.	OK							
I_elecSignal		Signal Generator | Emits a static electric signal	OK							
I_elecClock		Clock Signal Generator | Emits a square wave electric signal (2s frequency).	OK							
I_elecToggle		Flip-flop | Toggle its output (bottom-right) each time its input (bottom-left) goes from 0 to powered (rising edge).	OK	"It's a ""flip-flop"" logical/electronic component, the description is how it works. Here, it has one input and one output. Each time the input goes from 0 to 1 (logically), the output toggle (goes from 0 to 1 or 1 to 0)"						
I_elecDelay		Delay Gate | Set its output (bottom-right) as its input (bottom-left) after 1s of delay.	OK	It's an logical/electronic component. After one second of delay, the output of this electric component takes the value of its input						
I_elecWaterSensor		Water Sensor | Generate a signal if some water is detected (more than 20% of the cell).	OK							
I_elecAND		AND Gate | Generates a signal if both of its inputs on the left are not 0.	OK							
I_elecOR		OR Gate | Generates a signal if one of its inputs on the left are not 0.	OK							
I_elecXOR		XOR Gate | Generates a signal if (only) one of its inputs on the left is 0.	OK							
I_elecNOT		NOT Gate | Generates a signal if its input (bottom-left) is 0.	OK							
I_elecLight		Light Signal | Turns on when its outlet is powered.	OK 							
										
I_rocketTop		Rocket Top | Top stage of your salvation.	OK							
I_rocketTank		Rocket Tank | Middle stage of your salvation. You'll need 5 of them.	OK							
I_rocketEngine		Rocket Engine | First stage of your salvation.	OK							
										
										
// ==================== INGAME MESSAGES ====================										
										
DAMAGE_CRITICAL		{1} critical!	OK							
WATER_PERCENT		{1}%	OK							
WATER_PRESSURE		Pressure={1}	OK							
HP_BAR		HP:{1}/{2}	OK							
USE_TIPS		{Input_Use}	OK							
MODE_TIPS		{Input_Mode}	OK							
MESSAGE_CANNOT_SAVE		You cannot save during the night. Hold out until dawn!	OK							
MESSAGE_CANNOT_SAVE_BOSS		You cannot save near a boss. Move away or kill it!	OK							
MESSAGE_CANNOT_SAVE_LAUNCH		You cannot save during the rocket launch. Hold on!	OK							
MESSAGE_CANNOT_SAVE_CLIENT		Only the host can save or load in a multiplayer game.	OK							
MESSAGE_SAVING		Save game...	OK							
MESSAGE_SAVED		Game successfully saved as '{1}'.	OK							
MESSAGE_GAME_OVER		Game over.\nPlease reload a saved game. ({Input_QuickLoad} to reload the last one).	OK							
MESSAGE_GAME_DEAD		Respawning in {1}...	OK							
MESSAGE_GAME_DEAD_ALL		All players are dead: game over.\nThe host must reload a saved game.	OK							
MESSAGE_INTRO1		You are a representative of CRAFT & Co.\nYou are selling automated fabrication tools across the galaxy.	OK							
MESSAGE_INTRO2		Until the day you crash on a dangerous wild planet...	OK							
MESSAGE_CANNOT_DIG		You can't dig that, it's too resistant.\nUpgrade your Miniaturizor!	OK							
MESSAGE_CANNOT_DIG_BASALT		You can't dig that, it's incredibly resistant. \nOnly a powerful explosive could break it.	OK							
MESSAGE_TELEPORTER_UNPOWERED		The teleport entrance must be powered.	OK							
MESSAGE_TELEPORT_NOT_FOUND		Impossible to teleport, no other teleport was found.	OK							
MESSAGE_ROCKET_UNFINISHED		Your rocket is not complete. It needs 1 engine, 5 tanks and 1 top section.	OK							
MESSAGE_FINAL		Congratulations, you have escaped the planet!	OK							
MESSAGE_KILL_TIER2		Caution! If you kill a new species, they will attack you at night!	OK							
MESSAGE_ERROR_SAVE		Error! Cannot write the save file. Please check the disk access rights, free disk space, antivirus...\n\nError message: {1}	OK							
ROCKET_XXP		{1}%	OK							
ROCKET_50P		{1}%\nWaiting for pilot...	OK							
ROCKET_50P2		{1}%\nWaiting for {2} pilots...	OK							
MESSAGE_BONUS_1		A few years have passed.\nThanks to your personal experience, you have become a great salesman for Craft & Co.	OK							
MESSAGE_BONUS_2		And one day, you decide to go back to this infernal planet, with the latest Craft & Co inventions.\nNow it's your time to have fun!	OK							
MESSAGE_KICKED		You have been kicked by the host	OK							
MESSAGE_BANNED		You have been banned by the host	OK							
MESSAGE_HOST_NO_ANSWER		No answer from host. Please try again in a few second...	OK	the player who launch the multiplayer game is the host (and its machine is the server)						
MESSAGE_NO_LOBBY		Waiting for lobby creation...	OK							
CHAT_DEATH_KILLED		{1} was killed by a {2}.	OK							
CHAT_DEATH_FALL		{1} crashed.	OK							
CHAT_DEATH_DROWN		{1} drowned.	OK							
CHAT_DEATH_CRUSHED		{1} was crushed.	OK							
CHAT_DEATH_BURNT		{1} was burnt.	OK							
CHAT_DEATH_ROCKET		{1} sacrificed himself for the progress of Rocket Science.	OK							
CHAT_DEATH_OTHER		{1} died in unknown circumstances.	OK							
CHAT_PICKED		Picked up: {1} ({2})	OK	Displayed when the player walks over a item dropped by a monster (or mined by himself). It displayes as Picked up: dirt (14).  So {1} is the name of the item, and {2} is the number of this items the player already owns						
CHAT_NEW_PLAYER		{1} joined the game.	OK							
CHAT_NEW_PLAYER_WARNING		Warning: new player {1} is running a different game version (build {2}) than the host (build {3}). It could result in bugs.	OK							
MESSAGE_DIFFERENT_BUILD		Warning: host is running a different game version (build {1}) than your one (build {2}). It could result in bugs.	OK							
ENV_EXPECTED		ATTENTION: Natural disaster {1} expected in {2}s	OK							
ENV_ONGOING		ATTENTION: Natural disaster {1} ongoing, end in {2}s	OK							
ENV_heatWave		HEAT WAVE	OK							
ENV_rainFlood		RAIN FLOOD	OK							
ENV_meteorShower		METEOR SHOWER	OK							
ENV_volcanoEruption		VOLCANO ERUPTION	OK							
ENV_earthquake		EARTHQUAKE	OK							
ENV_quietNight		QUIET NIGHT	OK							
ENV_restlessNight		RESTLESS NIGHT	OK							
ENV_gravityWaves		GRAVITY WAVES	OK							
ENV_acidWater		ACIDIC WATERS	OK							
ENV_drowsiness		DROWSINESS	OK							
ENV_matingSeason		MATING SEASON	OK							
ENV_luckyDay		LUCKY DAY	OK							
ENV_sunEclipse		SUN ECLIPSE	OK							
ENV_mist		MIST	OK							
ENV_emp		ELECTROMAGNETIC DISTURBANCES	OK							
ENV_sharkstorm		SHARKSTORM	OK							
										
										
										
MESSAGE_CANNOT_SAVE_EVENT		Game cannot be saved during a '{1}' event	OK							
										
// ==================== MENUS ====================										
										
COMMON_YES		YES	OK							
COMMON_NO		NO	OK							
COMMON_OK		OK	OK							
COMMON_CANCEL		CANCEL	OK							
COMMON_ON		ON	OK							
COMMON_OFF		OFF	OK							
COMMON_+		+	OK							
COMMON_-		-	OK							
COMMON_CONFIRM		CONFIRM	OK							
COMMON_CLOSE_SIGN		X	OK	Do not translate						
										
CRAFT_ITEM		Item	OK							
CRAFT_COST		Cost	OK							
CRAFT_FILTER_ALL		ALL	OK							
CRAFT_FILTER_ALL_DESC		Show items of all categories 	OK							
CRAFT_FILTER_DESC		Only show items of category {1}	OK	{1} can be MINERALS, DEVICES, WEAPONS, etc.						
CRAFT_FILTER_ADD		Show all items	OK							
CRAFT_FILTER_ADD_DESC		Show weapons and non-consumable devices even if they (or their upgrade) are already in inventory, and Auto-Builder MK I.	OK							
INVENTORY_OPEN		... {Input_Inventory}	OK							
INVENTORY_PANEL		INVENTORY	OK							
HUD_MENU		MENU	OK							
HUD_HELP		?	OK							
HUD_DAY		DAY:\n{1}	OK							
HUD_COUNTDOWN		{1}	OK							
HOME_NEW		NEW	OK							
HOME_LOAD		LOAD	OK							
HOME_MULTI		MULTIPLAYER	OK							
HOME_HELP		HELP	OK							
HOME_OPTIONS		OPTIONS	OK							
HOME_QUIT		QUIT	OK							
HOME_VERSION		Dig or Die v{1}	OK							
HOME_INFOS_TITLE		TO LEARN MORE:	OK							
HOME_INFOS_1		Wiki	OK							
HOME_INFOS_2		Forum	OK							
HOME_INFOS_3		Twitter	OK							
HOME_INFOS_4		Facebook	OK							
HOME_INFOS_5		Discord	OK							
HOME_CONFIRM_DELETE_STATS		Are you sure you want to delete all your stats and achievements?	OK							
LAUNCHER_RES		Resolution:	OK							
LAUNCHER_FULL		Fullscreen:	OK							
LAUNCHER_PLAY		PLAY	OK							
PAUSE_TITLE		PAUSE	OK							
PAUSE_BACK		RETURN TO GAME	OK							
PAUSE_SAVE		SAVE	OK							
PAUSE_LOAD		LOAD	OK							
PAUSE_HELP		HELP {Input_Help}	OK							
PAUSE_OPTIONS		OPTIONS	OK							
PAUSE_QUIT		EXIT TO MAIN MENU	OK							
OPTIONS_TITLE		OPTIONS	OK							
OPTIONS_RES		Resolution:	OK							
OPTIONS_FULL		Fullscreen:	OK							
OPTIONS_AA		Anti-Aliasing:	OK							
OPTIONS_VSYNC		VSync:	OK							
OPTIONS_RUNINBACK		Run In Background:	OK							
OPTIONS_FRAMERATE		Max Framerate:	OK							
OPTIONS_FRAMERATE_DETAIL		Target framerate. Ignored if VSync is true	OK							
OPTIONS_KEYBOARD		Keyboard:	OK							
OPTIONS_LANGUAGE		Language:	OK							
OPTIONS_MUSIC		Music:	OK							
OPTIONS_SOUND		Sound:	OK							
OPTIONS_DIRECT_SHORTCUT		Use by shortcuts:	OK							
OPTIONS_DIRECT_SHORTCUT_DETAIL		Devices are activated or toggled when you press their shortcut, instead of being selected	OK							
OPTIONS_AUTOSAVE		Auto-Save Frequency:	OK							
OPTIONS_AUTOSAVE_DETAIL		Number of auto-save per day.	OK							
OPTIONS_SHAKING		Screen shaking:	OK							
OPTIONS_SHAKING_REDUCED		REDUCED	OK							
OPTIONS_MOUSE_LOCK		Mouse Lock:	OK							
OPTIONS_MOUSE_LOCK_DETAIL		Prevent mouse to go out of the game screen when in game.	OK							
OPTIONS_CONTROLS		Controls:	OK							
OPTIONS_CONTROLS_EDIT		EDIT...	OK							
OPTIONS_DEFAULT		DEFAULT	OK							
CONTROLS_TITLE		Controls	OK							
SAVE_TITLE_SAVE		SAVE GAME	OK							
SAVE_TITLE_LOAD		LOAD GAME	OK							
SAVE_QSAVE		QUICK SAVE {Input_QuickSave}	OK							
SAVE_QLOAD		LOAD LAST {Input_QuickLoad}	OK							
SAVE_SAVE		SAVE	OK							
SAVE_LOAD		LOAD	OK							
SAVE_DELETE		DELETE	OK							
SAVE_CONFIRM_OVERWRITE		Are you sure you want to overwrite?	OK							
SAVE_ENTER_NAME		Save name:	OK							
SAVE_CONFIRM_DELETE		Are you sure you want to delete?	OK							
SAVE_INVALID		Invalid file name	OK							
QUIT_CONFIRM		Are you sure you want to quit?	OK							
DIFFICULTY_TITLE		CHOOSE DIFFICULTY	OK							
DIFFICULTY_PEACEFUL		PEACEFUL	OK							
DIFFICULTY_PEACEFUL_SUB		You'll miss all the fun	OK							
DIFFICULTY_EASY		EASY	OK							
DIFFICULTY_EASY_SUB		Not that easy	OK							
DIFFICULTY_NORMAL		NORMAL	OK							
DIFFICULTY_NORMAL_SUB		Sorry, I meant hard	OK							
DIFFICULTY_HARD		HARD	OK							
DIFFICULTY_HARD_SUB		Rename the game to 'Dig and Die'	OK							
DIFFICULTY_BRUTAL		BRUTAL	OK							
DIFFICULTY_BRUTAL_SUB		Forget it	OK							
DIFFICULTY_TOOLTIP		Recommended difficulty for new players is EASY. When surviving the night is not challenging enough, try a higher difficulty.	OK							
LOADING		LOADING {1}%\n\n{2}	OK							
LOADING_ERROR		Cannot load this saved game, the file is not valid (error: {1}).	OK							
LOADING_ERROR_preV0.3		Cannot load this game, because the file is corrupted or was saved with an older version of the game (before the v0.3 update).	OK							
GENERATION_START		Creating land...	OK							
GENERATION_LIGHT		Creating lights...	OK							
GENERATION_WATER		Creating water...	OK							
GENERATION_PLANTS		Creating vegetation...	OK							
GENERATION_FINAL		World generation finalization...	OK							
CREDITS		CREDITS	OK							
HELP_NEXT		NEXT	OK							
HELP_PREV		PREVIOUS	OK							
HELP_CLOSE		CLOSE	OK							
MULTI_TITLE		MULTIPLAYER	OK							
MULTI_NEW		NEW GAME	OK							
MULTI_LOAD		LOAD GAME	OK							
MULTI_JOIN		JOIN	OK							
MULTI_OPEN_CHAT		Steam Chat	OK							
MULTI_ENTER_PASS		Enter password:	OK							
MULTI_ENTER_PASSWRONG		Wrong password	OK							
MULTI_REFRESH		REFRESH	OK	"Refresh various screens (like the multiplayer game list). Same meaning than the usual F5 ""refresh"" key in web browsers"						
MULTI_HOST		HOST	OK							
MULTI_GAMENAME		GAME NAME	OK							
MULTI_PARAMS		PARAMETERS	OK							
MULTI_DIFFICULTY		DIFFICULTY	OK							
MULTI_NB_DAYS		DAY	OK							
MULTI_NB_PLAYERS		PLAYERS	OK							
MULTI_PING		PING	OK							
MULTI_OPTIONS_TITLE		GAME OPTIONS	OK							
MULTI_OPTIONS_GAMENAME		Game Name:	OK							
MULTI_OPTIONS_DIFF		Difficulty:	OK							
MULTI_OPTIONS_VISIBILITY		Visibility:	OK	"Visibility of the game: it can be ""public"" or ""friends"" (only friends can see the game and join it)"						
MULTI_OPTIONS_PASS		Password:	OK							
MULTI_OPTIONS_START		START	OK							
MULTI_OPTIONS_VISIBILITY_PUBLIC		PUBLIC	OK							
MULTI_OPTIONS_VISIBILITY_FRIENDS		FRIENDS	OK							
MULTI_OPTIONS_VISIBILITY_SOLO		SOLO	OK							
CHARACTER_PANEL		CHARACTER CUSTOMIZATION	OK							
CHARACTER_GENDER		Gender:	OK							
CHARACTER_GENDER_M		Male	OK							
CHARACTER_GENDER_F		Female	OK							
CHARACTER_SKIN_COLOR		Skin Tone:	OK							
CHARACTER_HAIR_STYLE		Hair Style:	OK							
CHARACTER_HAIR_COLOR		Hair Color:	OK							
CHARACTER_EYES_COLOR		Eyes Color:	OK							
CHARACTER_RANDOM		Random	OK							
COMMON_CHEATED		Ultimate items:	OK							
COMMON_CREATIVE		Creative Mode:	OK							
COMMON_EVENTS		Hazardous Environment:	OK							
COMMON_EVENTS_TOOLTIP		Random and often catastrophic events occur regularly. At your own risk...	OK							
COMMON_NO_ACHIEV		This option deactivates achievements.	OK							
COMMON_CHEAT_WARNING		Are you sure you want to play creative mode? If you haven't finished the game it will REALLY spoil it for you. Think again, consider your options!	OK							
										
// ==================== HELP ====================										
										
										
HELP_P1		HELP: BASICS	OK							
HELP_P1_1		{1}Game Objective{2}: To build a rocket ship so you can escape the planet. 	OK							
HELP_P1_2		{1}Short-Term Goal{2}: Survive the nightly attacks of multiple groups of monsters every night by building defenses.	OK							
HELP_P1_3		{1}{Input_Left}, {Input_Right}, {Input_Up}{2} to move and jump. 	OK							
HELP_P1_4		{1}{Input_QuickSave}{2} and {1}{Input_QuickLoad}{2} to QuickSave and Quickload.	OK							
										
HELP_P2		HELP: INVENTORY AND ITEM BAR	OK							
HELP_P2_1		{1}Inventory{2}: {1}{Input_Inventory}{2} to open or close it. 	OK							
HELP_P2_3		{1}Select an item{2} by clicking on it or pressing {1}[1]{2}, {1}[2]{2}, {1}[3]{2}, etc. Go back the previous selection with {1}{Input_LastSelection}{2}.	OK							
										
HELP_P3		HELP: ACTIONS	OK							
HELP_P3_1		{1}To shoot{2} with the selected weapon: {Input_Fire}. Shoot sparingly to avoid weapon overheating.	OK							
HELP_P3_2		{1}To mine resources or retrieve items: {Input_Miniaturizor}{2} (a Miniaturizor must be on the item bar). {1}{Input_Fire} to repair{2} if the miniaturizor is selected.	OK							
HELP_P3_3		{1}To activate{2} a potion, or {1}toggle{2} a passive device, {1}{Input_Miniaturizor} on its icon{2}, or select it and {Input_Fire} anywhere.	OK	both {x} keywords will be replaced by key names / mouse buttons						
										
HELP_P4		HELP: CRAFT & BUILD	OK							
HELP_P4_2		{1}To create new items{2}, place an Auto-Builder on the ground and press {1}{Input_Use}{2}. Then click on the items you want to craft. You must have all the recipe ingredients.	OK							
HELP_P4_3		{1}TIPS{2}: {1}To prevent water from flooding your base{2}, build a solid roof and place entrance steps.	OK							
HELP_P4_4		{1}TIPS{2}: Constructions will collapse if not supported. But underground constructions are anchored to the background and will always be stable.	OK							
										
HELP_P5		HELP: NIGHT DEFENSE	OK							
HELP_P5_1		{1}At night a lot of monsters will attack you{2}. Prepare yourself with good weapons and wisely placed turrets.	OK							
HELP_P5_2		{1}TIPS{2}: Do not try to prevent the monster from getting to you by locking yourself inside walls. {1}Leave some well protected open entrances{2}.	OK							
HELP_P5_3		{1}Only the species you have already provoked by killing one will attack you at night{2}: be sure to be well prepared before killing a new species.	OK							
HELP_P5_4		{1}TIPS{2}: If you manage to survive the night without building a few turrets, that means you chose a game difficulty that is too easy!	OK							
										
HELP_P6		HELP: TIPS	OK							
HELP_P6_1		Most weapons have recoil: shoot below you to jump much higher!	OK							
HELP_P6_2		If you fall into a dark place, shoot your weapon to get a flash of light.	OK							
HELP_P6_3		{1}What to do at the start:{2}\n1) Pick-up the items on ground near the crashed ship.\n2) Get some minerals, materials and monster drops from around you.\n3) Use them to craft turrets and better weapons.\n4) Prepare your defenses to survive the first night!	OK							
										
HELP_P7		HELP: MULTIPLAYER	OK							
HELP_P7_1		If the ping is higher than 100, you will experience a lot of lag.	OK							
HELP_P7_2		Here you can see if the host has modified some custom parameters (more info in the wiki).	OK							
HELP_P7_3		Press {Input_Enter} to {1}write and send chat messages{2}, and {Input_PlayersList} to see the players list.	OK							
HELP_P7_5		In multiplayer you will {1}respawn at death, and drop a bit of minerals{2} (depending of the difficulty level). Bosses will respawn too (after one day).	OK							
HELP_P7_6		The host can {1}save{2}, {1}reload{2}, and use the chat commands: {1}/kick player-name{2}, and {1}/param variable = new-value{2}. More info in the wiki.	OK	"Do not translate the commands ""/kick"" and ""/param variable ="""						
										
										
// ==================== AI SHIP MESSAGES ====================										
										
AI_10		Wake up Captain!	OK							
AI_20		I don't want to stay in this wreckage forever.	OK							
AI_30		Don't worry about me just yet. Worry about staying alive!	OK							
AI_40		This planet's data is in my files. The life forms here get particularly aggressive at night if you disturb them. And I think we crash landed on top of something, I can detect some dead corpses under the wreckage... too late to play the peaceful ambassador!	OK							
AI_50		Prepare yourself before the sun goes down!	OK							
AI_60		Use your Auto-Builder to craft some turrets and better weapons.	OK							
AI_70_1		A lot of scrap metal broke off during the crash. Search the area for it!	OK							
AI_70_2		Your Auto-Builder should be able to process scrap metal back into useful Iron.	OK							
AI_70_3		They will surely attack in the night...if you provoke them!	OK							
AI_70_4		Killing even 1 of their kind will provoke the entire species.	OK							
AI_70_5		If I were you I would craft a better gun.	OK							
AI_70_6		Place some turrets to help protect yourself during the night.	OK							
AI_70_7		I detect flying insects nearby that seem to give off unusually large amounts of energy!	OK							
AI_70_8		You could dig a cavern and use the solid rocks to protect your back.	OK							
AI_70_9		If you think they are about to kill you, run! Use the kick-back from strong weapons fire to propel you even faster.	OK							
										
AI_1000		You survived the night, well done!	OK							
AI_1010		Now we need a rocket built to escape this isolated planet.	OK							
AI_1020		Craft better Auto-Builders until you are able to build rocket parts.	OK							
AI_1030_1		You may need some rare materials, although everything can be found on this planet.	OK							
AI_1030_2		The Auto-Builder technology has been calibrated to use only local materials.	OK							
AI_1030_3		Craft an Auto-Builder MK II, so that you can build better items!	OK							
AI_1030_4		I advise against exploring in the dark underground, until you have some good lights.	OK							
AI_1030_5		Light source items are crafted with the Auto-Builder MK II, so make one!	OK							
AI_1030_6		Your job at CRAFT & Co is to sell these Autobuilder contraptions...don't tell me you don't know how to use them!	OK							
AI_1030_7		In my files I can see this planet has a very humid climate. Try not to build your base in floodable areas.	OK							
										
AI_2000		You did it, you made a Mark II Auto-Builder! Nicely done.	OK							
AI_2010_1		Explore and mine underground if you're looking for a good source of Iron or Coal.	OK							
AI_2010_2		Build solid, stable walls to better fortify your base.	OK							
AI_2010_3		Scanners indicate uncommon plant life to the far west. They could help you craft the Mark III Auto-Builder.	OK							
AI_2010_4		Don't forget to craft lights to find your way in the subterranean depths.	OK							
AI_2010_5		You can build bridges and towers if done with care, you know.	OK							
AI_2010_6		Stabilize your structures by placing more walls and Iron Supports underneath and beside unstable looking structures.	OK							
AI_2010_7		Stability of your structures factor in how much weight is being supported.	OK							
AI_2010_8		In case you didn't realize it by now, I am your ship's Artificial Intelligence.	OK							
AI_2010_9		Wasn't this your first interstellar voyage? How did you manage to crash us already?	OK							
AI_2010_11		You just had to choose the wettest tropical rain forest planet in this Sector to crash on, didn't you!	OK							
AI_2010_12		Try to build a roof and some steps at the entrances of your base if you don't want the water to flood it.	OK							
AI_2010_13		Do you know you can grow all the plants and trees you see around here? Just transplant them or their seed, and if their living conditions are met they will grow and spread quite fast.	OK							
AI_2010_14		Most plants require some wet dirt and enough light to grow. Some of them require a specific soil, or to be immersed in water.	OK							
										
AI_3000		You now have a Mark III Auto-Builder, excellent!	OK							
AI_3010_1		I have completed a scan of the area and have located some Aluminum, but it is very deep underground.	OK							
AI_3010_2		Apologies for my bad English, my primary language is C++.	OK							
AI_3010_3		Hurry up and build a rocket so that I can upload my software and we can get off this rock!	OK							
AI_3010_4		I have scanned a plant with rare properties that grows only at high altitudes. Check the mountain to the East.	OK							
AI_3010_5		Gas Rock may be our ticket out of here, but the only traces I'm detecting are strangely above us. Search the skies!	OK							
AI_3010_6		Please hurry, I'm getting quite bored here.	OK							
AI_3010_7		Don't just stand around talking to me all day. Move your ass!	OK							
AI_3010_8		If I were you I would try not to prevent the monsters from coming during the night. I would let them come and kill them off, one by one.	OK							
AI_3010_10		Some rare plants require very specific conditions to grow. Like high water pressure, or no light at all.	OK							
AI_3010_11		Did you know that the water you can see here is not actually water? It's Polywater, a polymerized form of water which has the property of being compressible. Lucky for you, you didn't try to drink it!	OK							
										
AI_2010_10		I hope you plan to build me a nice little drone to use. I'm stuck here.	OK							
AI_DRONE_LAUNCH_IT		Now launch that drone so I can upload myself into it!	OK							
AI_DRONE_T1		Yeah baby! Feels good!	OK							
AI_DRONE_T2		Yeah, I've got a laser now! Fear me little monsters!	OK							
AI_DRONE_T3		Power overwhelming!	OK							
AI_DRONE_BETTER_HERE		Are you kidding me? I'm better in this one!	OK							
AI_DRONE_BACK_IN_SHIP		What am I doing back here? What happened to my drone!	OK							
AI_DRONE_GOT_YOU		Got you	OK	The AI companion of the player (in a flying drone) can say that after killing a monster						
AI_DRONE_MONSTER_KILL		M-M-M-Monster Kill!	OK	"IT's a reference to Unreal Tournament ""M-M-M-Monster Kill"" phrase, very well known amongst english-speaking players. So maybe not translate it, or find something similar in the japanese gamer culture ? This sentences can be told by the drone when he killed 5 monsters quickly in a row"						
AI_VOLCANO		Caution, this volcanic basalt emits radiation that causes interferences with the Jetpack.	OK							
AI_ARMOR		It seems that since you wear this very strong armor, weakest monsters won't dare to attack you.	OK							
										
										
AI_4000		Mark IV Auto-Builder, way to go! Look at all those new shiny items you can build.	OK							
AI_4010_1		I don't have much more advice for you, you seem to finally be getting the hang of this situation.	OK							
AI_4010_3		Explore further, always further.	OK							
										
AI_3010_9		Be very careful if you explore to the far west deep underground, I can sense an extremely strong life-form signature.	OK							
AI_4010_2		I should tell you that my sensors detected another strange life-form at high altitude. It looks like those little firefly insects, but with a much stronger energy signature!	OK							
AI_BOSS_DWELLER		My sensors cannot pass through this mountain's basalt minerals. Be careful when you explore its tunnels, I've no idea what you may find there.	OK							
AI_BASALT		Old basalt looks incredibly resistant, but the Miniturizor MK5 should be able to handle some of the recent formations	OK							
AI_OLD_BASALT		This old basalt looks too strong even for the Miniaturizor MK5. But some explosive should do the job.	OK							
AI_ORGANIC		I detect a very strange... thing... a life-form... I'm not really sure. It's somewhere far East of here.	OK							
AI_Lightonium		You might want to preserve some of those luminous rocks. Their light looks powerful enough to power solar panels!	OK							
										
AI_5000		Mark V Auto-Builder, finally! Now you have access to building a rocket to get us off this damned planet! What are you waiting for?	OK							
AI_5010_1		Explore further, always further!	OK							
										
AI_END_1		Ok I just uploaded myself into the rocket! Preparing for launch!	OK							
AI_END_2		Engine heating will take some time, and it will surely attract monsters from far away... be ready to protect me! I mean, protect the rocket!	OK							
AI_END_3		The doors must be sealed before continuing the launch sequence. Get in!	OK							
AI_END_4		And off we go!	OK							
										
										
AI_6000		Time for revenge!	OK	Told by the drone, in the game epilogue, when player comes back with super equipement (becoming very very powerful)						
AI_6001		Let's have fun!	OK	"same as for ""time for revenge!"""						
										
										
MESSAGE_OLD_BUILD		Warning: your game version (build {1}, branch '{2}') has to be updated in order to prevent bugs in multiplayer. Steam will automatically update the game after you quit it.	OK							
INPUT_Debug		Debug	OK							
LOADING_HOST_RELOAD		Host is reloading a previous save. Please wait...	OK							
DEV_MODE		Dev Mode	OK	do not translate						
										
										
// ========== MODIFS ON 2018 DECEMBER										
										
I_invisibilityDevice		Stealth Bracelet | Renders you partially invisible, so monsters will have a tougher time tracking you down. When they are not in night berserker mode, they will have to be closer than normal to detect you. Using a weapon cancels your invisibility.	OK							
I_elecProximitySensor		Proximity Sensor | Generates a signal if a unit is detected in front of the sensor. The 3 modes are: detect players (green), monsters (red), or both (blue).	OK							
I_elecAlarm		Alarm Signal | Flashes and emits sound when its outlet is powered.	OK							
I_wallCompositeDoor		Composite Door | Ultra robust and heavy door. If attached to an electric wire, it cannot be opened manually but only by an electric signal.	OK							
I_ultimateRebreather		Ultimate Rebreather | Gives you infinite oxygen from the water.	OK							
I_potionHpMega		Mega Health Potion | Fully restores your HP.	OK							
I_potionPheromones		Pheromones Potion | Attract monsters from far and wide. This potion is very dangerous, but useful for hunters!	OK							
I_potionInvisibility		Invisibility Potion | When they are not in night berserker mode, monsters will be unable to detect you for 1 min. Using weapons or items cancels the invisibility field.	OK							
I_elecDistanceSensor		Distance Sensor | Generates a signal if a unit is detected around the sensor. The 3 modes are: detect players (green), monsters (red), or both (blue). 	OK							
I_potionArmor		Armor Potion | Strengthens human tissue so it takes much less damage from external forces. Reduces damage by 30% over 60s.	OK							
I_generatorWater		Hydroelectric Power Generator | This generator produces electricity if there's enough water pressure. Water must flow from one side to the other, at least 3 blocks below the water surface on the input side. The more pressure, the more electricity is generated.	OK	The item produce electricity if there is enough water pressure. Water pressure is defined by the vertical distance (height) between the item and the water surface. This distance is measured in number of blocks						
										
MULTI_KICK		Kick	OK							
MULTI_BAN		Ban	OK							
DEVICE_TOGGABLE_DESC		\nTo toggle this item on/off, right-click on its icon or select it and left click anywhere.	OK							
HOME_CUSTOM		OTHER WORLDS	OK							
CUSTOM_TITLE		OTHER WORLDS	OK							
MULTI_MODE		WORLD	OK							
MULTI_OPTIONS_MODE		World:	OK							
MESSAGE_DELETE_ITEMS		Are you sure you want to delete all of your items '{1}' ?	OK							
INPUT_DeleteItem		Delete item	OK							
										
HELP_P2_2		{1}Items bar{2}: To easily use items in your inventory, place them on the items bar by double-clicking on them or dragging and dropping them.	OK							
HELP_P4_1		{1}To place an item on the ground{2}, select it and click on a cell near you, or just drag and drop the item (tip: you can place dirt, but not rock).	OK							
HELP_P7_4		You can {1}drag and drop items onto other player's names{2} to give items directly to them (even when very far away), or drag and drop them onto the ground to throw them.	OK							
										
AI_MINERALS_NEAR		I detect some precious minerals in the vicinity!	OK							
AI_1030_8		Dead monster's body parts are very valuable for the Auto-Builder, unfortunately, their blood turns radioactive at night, making those parts unusable.	OK							
OPTIONS_MUSICLICENSED		Licensed music	OK
HOME_PLANB		CHECK MY NEW GAME:	OK
										
I_flashLightMK3		Flashlight MK3 | Even more light!	OK							
I_miniaturizorMK6		Miniaturizor MK VI | Absolutely the best Miniaturizor ever invented.	OK							
I_betterPotionHpRegen		Better Health Regeneration Potion | The high radioactivity mixed with a multiple specials chemical ingredients helps the tissues to regenerate. Heals 400% of your HP over 60s.	OK							
I_defenseShieldMK2		Defense Shield MK2 | Creates a strong magnetic field around you that can absorb your maximum health points from projectiles. Refreshes in 2s.	OK							
I_waterBreatherMK2		Rebreather MK2 | This small device can get a large amount of oxygen from the water.	OK							
I_jetpackMK2		Jetpack MK2 | Portable double mini-rockets attached to a pack. Very heavy when walking or swimming. Doesn't work very well near volcanic Basalt (radiations and heat causing interferences).	OK							
I_antiGravityWall		Anti-Gravity Wall | How???	OK							
I_turretReparatorMK3		Auto-Repair Turret MK3 | Quickly repairs nearby damaged walls, turrets and machines. Consumes 2kW.	OK							
I_megaExplosive		Mega Explosive | Nuke.	OK							
I_turretParticlesMK2		Particle Turret MK2 | Long range and very incredibly powerful turret.	OK							
I_turretTeslaMK2		Tesla Turret MK2 | Creates a very powerful lightning strike on nearby monsters, with a area damage effect. Consumes 5kW.	OK							
I_collector		Collector | -Plants.	OK							
I_basaltCollector		Basalt Collector | -Basalt.	OK							
I_blueLightSticky		Blue Wall Light | You can attach this lamp to any surface and it will glow BLUE!	OK							
I_redLightSticky		Red Wall Light | You can attach this lamp to any surface and it will glow RED!	OK							
I_greenLightSticky		Green Wall Light | You can attach this lamp to any surface and it will glow GREEN!	OK							
I_turretLaser360		Rotating Laser Turret | Much more efficient than plasma technology with rotation! Burn through all organic material.	OK							
I_gunMeltdown		Gun "Meltdown" | The true power...	OK							